

www.heiux.com czarnecki.t@outlook.com +48 500 309 303

Work eligibility: EU (Polish citizen) China (family permit)

## Tomasz Czarnecki

### a Product Designer (UX/UI)

with an Intercultural Background

#### **Personal Statement**

A passionate **Product Designer (UX/UI)** and **Developer**, a **Problem Solver** with more than 7 years of overseas working experience.

Excellent **algorithmic thinking** skills and mission to create logical experiences combining user and business needs. Proven track record of intercultural work experience, including project managing roles.

Experienced in designing, introducing and maintaining **design systems**. Always focusing on providing experiences that are profitable and precisely adapted to the target group's needs.

Could contribute to your digital products since the research phase, through prototyping and front-end development. Additionally could help to upgrade existing products by providing heuristic evaluation, analytics, and user testing.

#### **Professional Experience**

**05.2021 - now** 6 months

**Senior Product Designer (UX & Gamification) •** Heineken • Amsterdam, Netherlands Skills: gamification, game ecconomy, design systems, prototyping, wireframing Tools: Figma, Adobe CC, Davinci Resolve

- Worked with BIG DATA & AI teams providing analytical solutions for Internal Users;
- Created an initial version of a Design System that increased product's coherence;
- · Introduced Gamification to increase Data Quality in the Heineken's Data Lake;
- Created a concept of a Gamified Solution that would spark bottom-up innovation;
- Applied intercultural proficiency to research users located on 6 continents;

**05.2020 - 05.2021** 1 year 1 month Product Designer (UX/UI) • macopedia.com • Poznan, Poland

Skills: design systems, problem solving, design thinking, usability testing, prototyping Tools: Figma, Adobe CC, Jira, Odoo, Mattermost

- Standardised company's workflow by introducing a cohesive Design System;
- Transferred design workflow to cloud-based software Figma;
- Organised a series of Figma lectures for co-workers;
- Worked independently with clients across the European Union;
- Encouraged usage of Design Thinking methodology in the company's strategy;

08.2019 - 05.2020

10 months

**Design Consultant • heiux.com • Worldwide** 

Skills: UX process, problem solving, design thinking, usability testing, prototyping Tools: Figma, Adobe XD, Adobe CC, Jira, Html, CSS, JavaScript, React

- After leaving the full-time position, worked as a Design Consultant;
- Worked location independently with European and Chinese clients;
- In spare time between project contributed UX Design to Open Source software;
- Expanded knowledge concerning Design Processes and Design Systems;

06.2017 - 07.2019

2 years 1 month

Project Architect • SEVEN International • Guizhou, China

Skills: Chinese, management, leadership, working with tight deadlines, recruiting Tools: Rhinoceros 3D, Lumion, Adobe InDesign/Photoshop

- Successfully led team of 10 Chinese-only speaking designers;
- Simultaneously managed teams located on 2 continents: in China and Poland;
- Provided conceptual designs for 4 Social Hosing projects and 5 local Banks;
- Led recruitment processes of 12 junior staff-members (for Polish office);
- Prepared series of Rhinoceros 3D courses (in Chinese office):
- Led client meetings and presentations for Chinese customers;

06.2016 - 06.2017

1 year

Parametric Designer • PWD Architecture • Beijing, China

Skills: sketching, research, concept design, working with tight deadlines Tools: Rhinoceros 3D, Grasshopper, C# Scripting, Adobe Illustrator/InDesign

- Played a crucial role in winning 21 million m<sup>2</sup> Urban Planning competition;
- Taught series of Grasshopper workshops for coworkers;

04.2015 - 05.2016

1 year 1 month

Parametric Designer • MAD Architects • Beijing, China

• Saved hundreds of working hours by providing complex parametric models;

08.2014 - 02.2015

7 months

Junior Architect • SEVEN International • Poznan, Poland and Guizhou, China

• Provided conceptions of buildings that were later realized by Chinese team;

09.2013 - 06.2014

9 months

Construction Site Intern • Budnex Developer • Gorzow, Poland

• Helped a construction site manager to supervise the quality of construction;

11.2012 - 02.2013

4 months

 $\textbf{Construction Site Manager/Translator} \bullet \textbf{Kaja Horeca Interieurs} \bullet \textbf{Netherlands}$ 

• Provided Polish-English translation on construction sites;

#### **Formal Education**

09.2014 - 04.2015

8 months

**Building and Environment Ph.D.** • Poznan Univeristy of Technology • Poland

- 2 semesters of Ph.D. studies realized at Faculty of Civil Engineering;
- Focused on Parametric Design: Grasshopper, C#, Algorithmic Thinking;

• Supervisor: prof. Ewa Pruszewicz-Sipińska, dean of the Architecture Faculty;

09.2011 - 06.2012

10 months

10 months

**Architecture Erasmus •** Istanbul Technical University • Turkey

• 2 semesters of international exchange;

03.2011 - 06.2014

3 years 4 months

Architecture M.Sc. • Poznan University of Technology • Poland

Architecture B.Eng. • Poznan University of Technology • Poland

• Graduated with the highest A-grade;

**09.2007 - 02.2011** 3 years 6 months

09.2006 - 06.2007

Computer Science B.Eng. • Poznan University of Technology • Poland

2 semesters of B.Eng. studies in English;

#### **Skills and Tools**

skills

- Problem solving
- Prototyping
- Design thinking

Working under pressure

Information architecture

- Usability testingUser research
- ManagementTeamwork

tools

• Figma

- Adobe CC
- React

Adobe XD

Git

Javascript

• Jira

- Npm/Node.js
- CSSHtml

• Odoo

Agile

• Chinese: B2

languages

• English: C2

Polish: Native

Courses and Trainings

**UX Design Masterclass** • by Matt Hryhorsky

Master Digital Product Design: UX Research & UI Design • by Rob Sutcliffe
UX Design & User Experience Design Course • by Daniel Walter Scott
User Experience Design - Adobe XD UI UX Design • by Daniel Walter Scott
Responsive Web Design - HTML5 CSS3 Bootstrap • by Daniel Walter Scott
UX & Web Design Master Course: Strategy, Design, Development • by Joe Natoli
The Complete Web Developer in 2019: Zero to Mastery • by Andrei Neagoie



www.heiux.com czarnecki.t@outlook.com +48 500 309 303

# Tomasz Czarnecki

a Product Designer (UX/UI)

with an Intercultural Background

#### **Cover Letter**

Dear Team,

my name is Tomasz. I am a passionate **Product Designer (UX/UI)**, who can code. I am a **Problem Solver** with excellent algorithmic thinking skills and more than 7 years of **overseas working experience**. I am proficient with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Jira, and GIT - currently learning React+Redux.

During these last years, I have had the chance to live and work in three different cultural backgrounds. I was born and raised in **Europe**, studied in the **Middle East**, and worked in **East Asia**. This unique cultural background taught me great respect for cultural diversity. I believe that every human being is unique and worth to be listened to.

I have a strong professional background in **Design** and **Computer Science**. For most of my professional career, I was working as a hybrid designer-developer using Grasshopper 3D visual programming language with Rhino Common library (https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Grasshopper\_3D). With my unique skill-set, I had a chance to contribute my time and talent to one of the most iconic buildings of the XXI century: **Harbin Opera House** in China (https://www.archdaily.com/778933/harbin-opera-house-mad-architects).

I am also a proficient Mandarin speaker. I had a chance to live and work for 5 years in China, where I grew and worked as a **Project Architect**. I successfully led projects, organized client presentations and design workshops - all in Chinese. I **managed** a team of Mandarin-only speakers to deliver high-quality designs within the deadlines.

I believe that the design process of every digital or physical product should be **user-oriented** - it is crucial for its success. But it also should be **business-centered** - as no product could exist without fulfilling its commercial goals.

For more information concerning my background please take a look at "About Section" of my webpage: <a href="https://www.heiux.com/">https://www.heiux.com/</a>

or my LinkedIn profile:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/tczarnecki/

If you have any questions please do not hesitate to contact me. I am looking forward to hearing from you!

Best Regards,

Tomasz Czarnecki